

# Philip Empl

Management Information Systems (M. Sc.)

- ▶ 20.08.1995 in Trostberg
- german
- unmarried

## **Skills**

Software development	6+ Jahre
Cyber security	4+ yrs.
Internet business/ E-commerce	4+ yrs.
Web development	2+ yrs.
Big data/ Data science	2+ yrs.
Distributed legder technology	2+ yrs.
Internet of things	1+ yrs.
Cloud computing	1+ yrs.
German	L1
English	C1

# **Biography**

I studied Management Information Systems at the University of Regensburg. My major fields of study were financial computing and cyber security in the Bachelor's program and cyber security in the Master's program. Since September 2020, I am a research assistant at the Chair of Information Systems I (Prof. Dr. Pernul). There I am involved in a research project funded by the Federal Ministry for Economic Affairs and Energy (BMWi).

My research topics are cyber security and data analytics in the context of the Internet of Things (IoT).

# Work experience

## Research assistant | PhD student

09/2020 - today

Chair of Information Systems (Prof. Pernul) University of Regensburg

Areas of responsibility: technical implementation of the respective work packages in the research project SISSeC and teaching.

### Part-time research assistant

03/2020 - 08/2020

Chair of Information Systems (Prof. Pernul) University of Regensburg

Areas of responsibility: participation in the research project SISSeC, funded by the German Federal Ministry of Economics and Energy, design of a buffer and persistence system and implementation of a digital twin.

## Trainer - Cyber security I

09/2019 - 02/2020

Chair of Information Systems (Prof. Pernul) University of Regensburg

Course contents: live Hacking (SQL injection), classical cryptography, modern cryptography (AES, DES), cryptanalysis, identification and authentication, rights management.

# Trainer - Information systems: developments and trends

03/2019 - 08/2019

Chair of Information Systems (Prof. Pernul) University of Regensburg

Course contents: introduction to PL/SQL, procedures and functions, trigger programming, object relational extensions in PL/SQL, NoSQL basics.

### Trainer - Cyber security I

10/2018 - 03/2019

Chair of Information Systems (Prof. Pernul) University of Regensburg

Course contents: live Hacking (SQL injection), classical cryptography, modern cryptography (AES, DES), cryptanalysis, identification and authentication, rights management.

## **Education**

10/2017 - 07/2020

# Management Information Systems (M.Sc.)

University of Regensburg

Cyber security • Data science
Master's thesis: "From edge to
cloud: an explorative study of IoT
data exchange and analysis".

10/2014 - 08/2017

# Managment Information Systems (B.Sc.)

University of Regensburg

Cyber security • E-Commerce
Bachelor's thesis: "Addressing the inefficiency of searching backward: a novel tool to support authors of literature reviews".

09/2006 - 06/2014

#### A-Level

Maximillian-von-Montgelas High School Vilsbiburg

Mathematics • German • English

■ Economics ■ Music.

## Interessen

- Guitarist at Edit.Sprinter
- DIY projects
- Fitness
- Smart home
- ▶ Animal protection organization

# Kontakt

- Kumpfmühler Str. 59D-93051 Regensburg
- □ +49 152 0986 5490
- mail@philipempl.de
- ifs.uni-regensburg.de
- github.com/philipempl
- xing.com/Philip\_Empl

#### Part-time research assistant

04/2018 - 10/2018

Professorship of Business Informatics (Prof. Schryen) University of Regensburg

Areas of responsibility: support in EPIQUALIS (epistomological progress through qualitative literature reviews), creation of literature data sets, static data analysis, research documentation, identification and authentication, use of Docker, Git, Python and R.

## Internship

10/2017 - 03/2018

Supply chain management BMW AG Landshut

Areas of responsibility: further development of the digital process board, coresponsibility for its rollout, implementation of a setup checklist, actual recording of the cycle times of processes.

### Student assistant

04/2017 - 10/2017

Professorship of Business Informatics (Prof. Schryen) University of Regensburg

Areas of responsibility: support in EPIQUALIS (epistomological progress through qualitative literature reviews), creation of literature data sets, static data analysis, research documentation, identification and authentication, use of Docker, Git, Python and R.

### Trainer - Theoretical computer science

10/2016 - 03/2017

Professorship of Business Informatics (Prof. Schryen) University of Regensburg

Course contents: introduction of automata, deterministic finite automata, non-deterministic finite automata, regular expressions and languages, context-free grammar and languages, push-down automata, introduction of Turing machines, decision problems.

## Working student

03/2015 - 08/2016

Manufacturing executive systems DRÄXLMAIER Group Vilsbiburg

Areas of responsibility: refactoring of the DTO model classes in the MES/ PCM software project, tests within the scope of the MES rollout, processing of various issues, wiki.

## **Publications**

 Wagner, G. & Empl, P. & Schryen G. (2020). "Designing a novel strategy for exploring literature corpora". In: *Proceedings of the 28th European Conference on Information Systems (ECIS)*, Marrakesch, June 15-17, 2020.

Regensburg, 1st October 2020

Philip Empl